最困难的地方挖通了
We're through the hard part.
再挖十八英尺就能见到管道了
Another 18 inches, we'll hit that pipe.
也许星期五就能完成
We'll be there by Friday.
我们可以好好谈谈了 不是吗？
Now, we got a hell of a lot to talk about, don't we?
这家伙说他是在这里干的
This guy says he's on the job in here.
混凝土是我的专项
Concrete is my speciality.
好的 警官 我们要他了
OK, boss. Sign him up.
白人不要你 黑人也不要你
Whites don't want you, blacks don't want you.
你被夹在了中间 不是吗 典型的两头不是人
You're just caught in the middle, aren't you?A regular tweener.
-喂  -是我
-Hello?  -It's me.
-是时候了  -好的
-It's time.  -Yes.
你怎么这么愤世嫉俗
Why are you so cynical?
迈克尔这是人情冷暖和现实主义
I think there's cynicism and then there's realism.
还有乐观主义 希望 信念
And there's optimism. Hope. Faith.
谢谢你逗我笑 但我今天心情不好
Thank you for trying to make me smile.Not today.
难说噢
You never know.
你想知道库珀的事？ 我无可奉告  因为我不是他
You want the Cooper story?I can't give it to you.Cos I'm not him.
你们想干掉的那两个律师仍然在逃
The lawyers, they're still running around.
那个小孩子也一样
Same thing goes for the kid.
接下来的事都交给我处理 马上
You gotta hand the reins over to me. Now.
请...
First of all...
你和你搭档将停职等候进一步通知
You and your partner are off the job until further notice.
那个
That one
-眼光不错  -谢谢
-Nice choice  -thanks
铂金的
Platinum.
表面抛光
Brushed.
-6.25盎司?  -6.25盎司
-6.25?  -6.25.
你的女人真幸福
She's a lucky woman.
是的 很幸福
Yes,she is.
你保留了它
You kept it.
留着什么？
Kept what?
那花
The flower.
我就像耗子 从来不扔东西
I'm a pack rat. I never throw anything out.
是啊 看这里一团糟 印象深刻
Yeah. All this clutter, it's overwhelming.
你要看看我住的住处再下结论
You should see my apartment.
我们连一次约会都没有过
Haven't even had our first date yet,
你就邀请我去你家了
and you're already inviting me in.
我还以为你是个正经的女孩
I thought you were a nice girl.
大家都知道正经女孩 总要最后才找到归宿
Michael, we all know nice girls finish last.
那你的归宿在哪里?
So where do you finish?
那要看我遇到谁了 深呼吸
That depends on where I start. Deep breath.
呼气
Exhale.
吸气
Inhale.
莎拉 外面缺人手
Sara, we're backing up out here.
好的 抱歉
Right. I'm sorry.
我去给你拿针剂
I'm gonna get your shot.
这个不是我的目的
This is not what I signed on for.
你想要我们怎么做? 摇白旗?还是叫中场暂停?
What do you want us to do?Wave the white flag?
我只是不想让林肯死
I just want to get Lincoln off death row.
林肯
Lincoln?
我们刚刚了解到 副总统莱娜斯从研究项目中
Vice President Reynolds funnelled millions
抽取了巨额资产注入她弟弟的公司
of dollars into her brother's company.
这笔资金有被分散到很多小帐户上
That money was filtered into small accounts
成为她竞选资金的主要来源
that made small donations to her campaign,
让她成为自由世界的下一界领袖
setting her up to be the leader of the Free World.
现在我们要做的  不止是阻止死刑这么简单
This doesn't end with us stopping an execution.
对我来说  是的
For me it does.
好了 换岗
OK. Let's rotate.
后庭花中士 轮到你下去了
Sergeant Sodomy, you're up next.
拉我一把
Come on.
我不了解你 但...
I don't know about y'all, but...
这地方对我来说太"黑"了  我挖不了
This room is getting a little too dark for me to dig.
你是说 这个监狱居然有个洞 你不愿意"进"的?
Are you telling me that there's a hole in Fox River that you don't want to get into?
什么?
what
嘿 别闹事
Hey. No one gets hurt.
我就弄不明白了
Hey, you know, I got a question.
那边的"小面条"怎么就连铲子都不用抓
Now, how come Fusilli over here ain't grabbing a shovel?
我在这里当家
I handle arrangements on the outside.
真的吗?还有文件证书什么的吗?
Really? What is that?Transport, paper, what?
没错 所以这里我说了算
Exactly. Makes me manager.
而我们就是些苦力了
And that makes us just labour, right?
现在你明白了
Mm-hm. Now you're getting it.
当家的最好留意这里的情况
You know, management better keep a close eye on the conditions up in here.
不然苦力也会罢工的 知道吗？
Or the labour's liable to go on strike.
回去干活
Get back to work.
狱警来了
Whoa, CO coming.
把那个放回那里
Put that back up there.
斯科菲尔德
Scofield
跟我走
Move it.
夫妻探访时间
It's time for your conjugal.
你老婆来了
Your wife is here.
你是斯科菲尔德夫人
So you're Mrs Scofield?
你以前来过吗
Ever done this before?
我是说 夫妻探访
Had a conjugal, I mean.
没
No.
别担心 我只是想聊聊
Don't worry,I'm just trying to make conversation.
没问题
Clear.
你对她有印象吗?
She look familiar to you?
没有 长官
No, Captain.
我好像哪里见过她
I know her from somewhere.
你来了
You came.
是的
Of course.
你近来怎么样？
How've you been?
很好 我找了个工作
Fine. I found a job.
好啊 我替你高兴
Good. I'm glad.
在这里很糟吧？
Is it awful, being here?
记得你呆的第一个地方吗？
Remember the first place you stayed?
机场边的旅馆
That hotel, by the airport?
区别只是69美元的房租和免费的洗发水
Only difference is $69 and the free shampoo.
你还是一副勇敢的表情
Always the brave face.
你还戴着它
You're still wearing it.
每天都戴
Every day.
我很担心你
I worry about you.
别这样
Don't.
还能为你做点别的什么吗？
Is there anything else that I can do?
就事先约定的可以了
Just what we agreed on.
他们搜查我的时候我很害怕
I was so nervous when they were checking.
有个问题
One question.
在监狱里要信用卡有什么用？
Why would you need a credit card in prison?
看来监狱暴动并没有改变任何事
The riot didn't change anything.
你有看过我们的预算裁减计划吗?
Have you seen the budget cuts?
医疗保险方面又减少了10%
Another 10% from healthcare.
疾病预防方面35%
And 35 from prevention.
他是州长 但他同时也是你父亲
He's the governor, but also your father.
或许他认为只要他减得够狠 他们就没钱雇你了
Maybe he thinks if he cuts enough,they can't afford you.
你也知道夫妻探访后的例行步骤吧 斯科菲尔德?
You understand this is standard procedure following a conjugal, right?
总要小心才是
Never can be too careful.
好了 弯腰
All right. Bend over.
在房间里和那妞过的愉快吧
You have a good time in the romper room with that Euro?
随你说好了 老大
Whatever you say, boss.
她以前来过吗?
She come around here before?
-第一次来  -真的?
-First time.  -You sure?
因为我好像在哪里见到过她
Cos damn if I don't recognise her from somewhere.
或许她还有什么别的人要探访
Maybe she visits some other con.
一石二鸟
Killing two birds with one bone.
-明白我的意思吗?  -我不想明白
-Catching my drift?  -I wouldn't know.
好了 没问题 长官
All right. He's clear, Captain.
最好去洗个澡 斯科菲尔德
Make sure you take a shower, Scofield.
天知道有些女人会给你带来什么
You never know what some women can give you.
你知道这个的 不是吗?
You know this one, don't you?
嘿 来点反应啊
Come on, gimme something.
我以为你们黑鬼都有音乐天赋
I thought you was a musical people.
你老子有你这么个儿子一定很自豪
You know, your parents must be so proud of you, man.
就像中了头彩一样
Hitting the trailer park trifecta.
种族主义 恋童癖
You're a racist, a paedophile,
呆头呆脑
and stupid.
我真的很气愤
You know, it vexes me that
在这个屋子里就我被认为是坏家伙
I'm made out to be the bad guy in the room.
你们难道都是 因为偷小女孩的饼干才被抓进来的
Y'all ain't here for stealing Girl Scout cookies.
我们可没有在偷饼干时 杀卖饼的小女孩
None of us murdered any Girl Scouts in the process.
迈克尔回来了
Michael's coming back from the boneyard.
一个人
Alone, alone.
我把我和玛丽克鲁兹的事情都告诉你了
I tell you everything about me,
你居然连你结婚了都不告诉我
you don't tell me you're married?
以后再说
Later.
狂野一日游啊 斯科菲尔德?
Rough day, huh, Scofield?
我们这些人在这里搞混凝土
While the rest of us are in here slinging concrete,
而你却让马子来擦你生了锈的长枪
you got some little girl in to play on your rusty trombone, huh?
这家伙说得没错
Man's got a point.
这有点不公平 知道我说什么吧?
It just doesn't seem equitable, like.
闭嘴干你的活 帝博格
Shut up and dig, T-Bag.
我想我们这里的人是想知道
I think what the idiots inside want to know is,
当我们在这里挖洞的时候 你都在干些什么?
while we're digging this hole,what are you doing?
我要去购物了
I'm going shopping.
很好
We're good.
没有人
All clear.
信用卡
Credit card?
狱警要是发现你有这个 他们会让你吃不了兜着走 那你就...
The bulls catch you with that, they'll be so far up your doggy door...
别担心
Don't worry.
他们逮不到我的
They won't be catching me with one.
-你这么肯定?  -因为...
-How you so sure?  -Because...
我并没有信用卡
I don't have a credit card.
尼克
Nick?
救命!
Help! Please...
我遇上车祸了 我的车毁了...
Please, I had an accident, my car is totalled.
我需要...求你们了...有人在吗?
Is there anybody there?
我们不能不理他
We can'tjust ignore him.
管不了这么多了
The hell we can't.
求求你们
Help me. Please!
帮帮我 求你们了
Help me, please.
噢 老天啊
Ow! God!
发生什么了?
What happened?
呃...我一定是睡着了 我开了12小时的车
I must've dozed off.I've been driving for 12 hours.
我要去井里打点水吗?
Should I get some water from the well?
-井已经干枯了 -老天 我的腿
-No, the well's dried up.  -Oh,god my leg.
我想这里应该有个急救包的
I think there's a medical kit over here.
都别动
No one's going anywhere.
和小家伙说再见吧
All right. Say goodbye to Junior.
你知道人体有多少品脱的血吗?
You know how many pints of blood the human body has?
答案是十 十品脱
The answer is ten. Ten pints.
你看那边地板上的迷人王子还有多少血来流?
How many you think Prince Charming over there on the floor has left?
八?还是七?
Eight, going on seven?
跟你说吧 我要带他去柴房那边谈谈
I'm gonna take him out to the woodshed, have a little talk.
同时希望你认真考虑一下
In the meantime,I want you to chew on this.
你告诉我你发现的布伦斯案子所有事
You tell me everything about the Burrows case,
还有你告诉了谁 那样的话
and who else you've told about it,
我可能会让你带萨维恩先生及时就医
and there's a chance that I might let you go in time to get Mr Savrinn to a doctor.
由你决定谁的命更重要
You decide whose life is more valuable.
是那个已经是在等死的家伙
The guy waiting to die on death row,
还是这个可能要死在柴房里的家伙
or the guy wishing he'd die out in the woodshed.
一件外套 黑色
One suit, black.
一双袜子 黑色
One pair of socks, black.
一双鞋
One pair of shoes.
鞋带
Shoelaces.
一个袖珍录音机
One small tape recorder.
一只金表
One gold watch.
你住过高级旅馆吗?LJ
You ever stayed at a fancy hotel, LJ?
早上你离开房间的时候 一塌糊涂
You leave your room in the morning, it's a mess.
湿的脏毛巾扔在浴室地上
Wet dirty towels on the bathroom floor,
昨晚送来的外卖变质发臭
last night's room service stinking to high heaven.
但是 晚上你回到房间的时候  它们不见了
Then, you come back at night, it's all gone.
新的毛巾  干净的床单  枕头上的糖
Fresh towels, sheets, candy on the pillow.
简直是世界上最美好的感觉
It's just the best feeling in the whole world.
有人替你收拾了一切
Cos someone else cleaned up your mess.
你只需要出去散散步
All you had to do was walk away.
不准你伤害他们
Don't you hurt them.
好
OK.
但你要告诉我他们知道多少  他们还告诉了哪些人
But you gotta tell me exactly what they know and who else they've told,
那样今晚就没人会死
and nobody has to die tonight.
你出去散散步  让我来收拾
You just walk away. Let me clean up your mess.
我根本不知道怎么回事  我向上帝发誓!
I don't know what's going on.I swear to God.
真希望我可以相信你
Well, I wish I could believe that.
贝利克指派了一个新室友给我
Bellick assigned me a new cellmate.
什么样的?
Who'd you get?
某个新来的笨蛋  偷钱包偷到一个休班警员头上
Some new fish. Ran a bump and swipe on an off-duty cop.
手快  嘴更快
Fast hands, faster mouth.
哟  聊什么呢兄弟们?
Yo, what's cracking, my peoples?
说曹操 曹操到 迈克尔斯科菲尔德 这是大卫·阿克斯
Speak of the devil.Michael Scofield, David Apolskis.
你好
S'up?
我见过你  对吧? 你是PI的
I seen you before, right? You're part of that PI crew.
也许你能让我参一份
Maybe you can hook me up.
你知道 兄弟我也要弄点绿色
Brother needs to make some green
绿色的钞票  你懂我意思?
some cashish, you know?
时薪19美分
The pay is 19 cents an hour.
19美分 简直是奴役
19 cents? That's slavery, yo.
这里是监狱哟
That's prison, yo.
何况  PI已经满人了
And besides, PI's all full up for now.
好吧  我理解你的意思
All right. I feel you.
如果有什么好处 记得关照小弟一下  好吧?
But keep a brother in mind, if something opens up, yo.
我宁愿付19美分一个小时 出来多放风一会儿
Hell, I'll pay 19 cents an hour to get me some more time out of the block.
像重新养一个孩子
Like having another kid.
我已经养大了一个  再来一次可受不了
Already raised one. I'm too old to do it again.
你听过有囚犯入狱前保管的财物 被盗的事情吗?
You ever hear of anything being stolen from R&D?
当然
Of course.
狱警经常偷偷拿东西
Bulls steal from personals all the time.
问题是
Problem is,
只有到出狱领回财物  你才会知道他们拿了什么
you never know what's gone until you're outside of the walls.
那时你也无能为力了
At that point, you can't do anything about it.
如果是现在知道呢?
What if you knew now?
听着 我说过了  无论你计划做什么  不要拉我下水
Look, I told you. Leave me out of whatever it is you've got going.
我只想问你是否见过 某个狱警戴着一只金表
I just need to know if you've seen a guard with a gold watch.
很多人可以给你搞一块金表进来
There's a lot of people can get you a gold watch in here.
对  但是我就需要这块
Yeah, but I need this specific gold watch.
韦斯特莫兰德
Westmoreland.
狱长要你去一下
Pope wants to see you.
走吧!
Let's go.
听着  我没看见有
Look, I haven't seen nothing.
但有那么一个狱警
But there is this one CO.
称得上是全监狱最菜的扒手
Word is he's the worst thief in here.
我老婆从县档案处 给你发的传真
My wife faxed this over from County Records.
斯科菲尔德的结婚证明复印件
Copy of Scofield's marriage licence.
她说你欠她个大人情
She says you owe her, big time.
看来是真的  他不是随便找个婊子来扮老婆
Looks legit. He wasn't trying to sneak in some whore for a conjugal.
这里写着  他是在抢劫前一天结婚的
Says here they got married the day before Scofield robbed that bank.
为什么他要那样做?
Why the hell would he do that?
-有维罗妮卡的消息?  -没有
-Heard from Veronica?  -No.
LJ送来个便条  说跟她在一起 很安全
Just a note from LJ saying he was with her, he's safe.
但已经有一段时间了  有点不对劲
But it's been a while. Doesn't feel right.
不对劲
Feels wrong.
非常不对劲
Really wrong.
我 呃...
I, uh...
我终于意识到
I've come to a realisation.
要么多诺万小姐和那男孩 并不在喜欢你
Either Ms Donovan and that boy don't like you very much,
要么他们对你的生存能力 抱有难以理解的信心
or they have an unreasonable amount of faith in your cardiovascular system.
告诉我吧 尼克 这就是你拿到的全部?
So tell me, Nick.This all you got?
一份毫无根据的申诉?
This paper trail of an indictment that never even happened?
就这么多?
Is this it?
我们知道你们丢了那盘录像带
We know you don't have a surveillance tape any more,
我们知道你们再也没有证人
you have nobody to testify.
你们就剩那么一点东西?
So is this really all you've got?
萨维恩先生  穿过你大圆肌的那颗子弹
Mr Savrinn, that bullet went through your teres major,
扯碎了你肩胛骨外侧的肌肉
ripped the lateral margin of your scapula,
使你的手臂完全不能转动
leaving you no medial rotation of your arm.
所以如果你想用那块木头打我
So if you try to swing that piece of lumber at me...
手臂就会疼的像断掉一样
It's gonna feel like your arm is ripping out of its socket.
来吧  尼克 "正义计划"先生
Come on, Nick. Mr Project Justice.
我们都知道你为什么坐在这里
We both know why you're really here, don't we?
你并不是为了救林肯·布伦斯
And it ain't to save Lincoln Burrows' life.
在这高墙里  我缓慢的爬行
Inside these walls, I creep and I crawl,
寻找一条逃生的路子  但是我知道这却不是一件好差事
looking for a way out, But I know there's gonna be no easy route
这将是12个轮回... 12个轮回一个周期
This is gonna be a 12-round...12-round bout
和贝利克一起 帝博格在我脑海里...
Bellick and T-Bag on my mind
这真是遭罪...
This grind in here...
还有兴趣参加劳动团吗?
You still interested in getting in on PI?
我母亲是女人吗?
Does my momma got big breastices?
我可不知道
I wouldn't know.
她当然是女人  而我当然愿意
Hell, yeah, she does. And hell, yeah, I do.
好吧  听着  帮我个忙
All right, look. I need a favour.
听说你是个老练的街头扒手
Word is you made your trade as a snatch and grab.
没错
That's right.
我要你帮我 偷一件被别人偷走的东西
I need you to steal something back that was stolen from me.
一件什么东西?
What kind of something?
一块手表
Just a watch.
绝对不止一块手表那么简单
Uh-uh. There ain't no such thing as just a watch.
每样东西都有它不同的偷法
Every design has a different clasp,
每种扣子都有不同的偷法
every clasp has a different swipe.
意大利表  Remedi
It's Italian. A Remedi.
金表带  珍珠面  全天候
Gold band, pearl face, all-weather.
-哪一年?  -2003
-What year?  -2003.
那玩意儿有个蝴蝶扣
That's a butterfly clasp on that bitch.
-什么意思?  -内藏结构
-Which means what?  -Hidden deployment.
所以没法把它扒走 而不引起任何感觉
There ain't no way to snatch it without the mark feeling it.
所以要偷它  必须用我的独门秘方
Which just means I'm gonna have to get whimsical on this ficky.
我偷到表  你就让我进囚犯劳动团?
I get you this watch, that means I get in on some PI?
我会考虑  但不一定
It means I'll think about it. No promises.
为什么你那么急着想要这块表?
Why you need this watch so bad, anyway?
它对我的某个家人意义重大
Let's just say it means a lot to someone in my family.
进来  查尔斯  坐下
Come in, Charles. Sit down.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
我有个坏消息  查尔斯
I've got some bad news, Charles.
你的女儿得了重病
Your daughter is very sick.
她得了食道癌
She's got oesophageal cancer.
她在印第安那波利斯的圣心医院
Now, she's at Sacred Heart, in Indianapolis,
她想在最后的时间里见到你
and she wants to see you while there's still time.
还有多久?
How much time?
医生说只有几周
Doctors say a few weeks.
问题是  惩教署不打算让你去
The problem is, the DOC isn't gonna let you go.
他们认为你还具有危胁
They think you're still a flight risk.
-她是我唯一的孩子  -我知道
-She's my only child.  -I know that.
相信我  查尔斯 我用你的良好记录做过申诉
Believe me, Charles, I've lobbied on your behalf.
这是本州的政策
It's state policy.
只有葬礼可以得到临时出狱许可
They will only extend furloughs in the case of funerals.
你是在说
You're telling me
我必须等到她死了 才可以见到她?
I have to wait until she dies before I see her?
斯科菲尔德先生  今天将会由我为你注射
Mr Scofield. Looks like I'll be administering your shot today.
唐克雷蒂医生呢?
Where's Dr Tancredi?
今天日程很满  她有其他病人
We've got a busy schedule today.She's with another patient.
按住他  别让他掉下推床!
Hold his legs! Hold his legs down!
按住脚!按住他的脚!
嘿  我们需要医生!
Hey, we need a doctor here!
好了 发生什么事?
What happened?
我不知道 这孩子正在吃饭 突然间
The kid was in chow, all of a sudden
他就发病了 开始呕吐
he collapsed and started spitting up his food.
看来他正在痉挛
Looks like some kind of seizure.
把他抬上来
Get him up here.
别让他伤到自己
make sure he doesn't hurt himself.
我需要氧气和镇静剂
I'll need O2 and cardio from you.
按住他  按住他!
Hold him. Hold him!
多诺万小姐  你的不动产法律经验
So, Ms Donovan.How is that background in real estate law going for you?
真的派上用场了?
Is it a big help?
我们终于取得点突破了
Well, frankly I think we caught a break.
林肯有个比他聪明很多的女友
If Lincoln had nailed a girl with half a brain,
她几乎快要解决这件事了
she probably would have brought this whole thing down already.
但你知道坏的部分是什么?
But you know what the worst part is?
你拖了一群人下水
You dragged these people
明知自己无法让他们脱身
into this knowing that you had no clue how to get them out.
我是说  如果你不那么好管闲事
I mean, if you had just minded your own business,
像莱提莎·巴里斯这样的人
people like Leticia Barris,
现在就不会死都没人知道
she wouldn't have a mouthful of maggots now.
你的未婚夫也不会倒毙在公寓
Your fiance would not be lying in his apartment
等着尸体开始发臭
waiting for the smell of his rotting corpse
以便邻居可以闻到才发觉他死了
to let the neighbours know that something had gone horribly wrong.
没错  他们的死就是因为你
That's right.Their deaths are on your head.
你造成的
You made this mess.
不是别人 是你
Nobody else. You.
但同样是你 可以让这一切结束
But you are also the one person that can end it all right here.
我只想知道你还牵扯了谁
All I need to know is who else you've involved.
你可以点头 让我知道你愿意说
So you just nod, and I'll know you're ready to talk.
你知道 多诺万小姐 我觉得 呃
You know, Ms Donovan, I think that
看来你有点着凉
you look a little cold.
也许这样你能让你更容易说出来
Maybe you'll find it easier to talk
你就可以说话了
after you've warmed up a little...
他在哪?发生什么了?
Where is he? What happened?
我们要离开这里 快点 没时间了 快点!
We gotta move. Come on, we don't have time. Come on.
快点 我们离开这里
Come on. We're getting out of here.
钥匙在哪?
Where are the keys?
口袋里
Pocket. Left.
把车打着!
Start the car.
他会没事吗?
Is he gonna be all right?
去把车打着 LJ!
Go start the car, LJ.
我们会把你送去医院 好吗?
Come on. We're gonna get you to a hospital.
我室友送你的礼物
A gift from my cellmate.
谢谢你 和他
Thank you. And thank him.
这只表  有什么特别?
The watch. What's it for, anyway?
我以为你不想知道我的计划
Thought you didn't want to know about this.
情况变了
Things have changed.
我要加入
I want in.
为什么这么突然?
Why the sudden change of heart?
我有我的理由
I have my reasons.
千万别选错路
Don't take this the wrong way,
每个加入的人  都得给其他人一个交待
but everyone who's in is bringing something to the table.
用钱来作交待怎样?
How about money?
-我们在谈多少钱?  -我以为你知道
-How much?  -I think you know.
我只记得某些谈话 最后以"我不是D.B.库珀"结束
I remember several conversations that ended with "I am not DB Cooper".
-我说谎  -你说谎?
-I lied.  -You lied.
我们是罪犯 我们擅长那样做
We're cons. We tend to do that.
我查过你的辩护词
I checked your alibi.
根据记录 库珀劫持飞机时 你确实正在被监禁
According to records, you were incarcerated at the time of the Cooper hijacking.
我父亲和我  都有共同的缺点就是赚容易钱
My father and I share more than just a weakness for easy money.
我们还有同样的名字
We also share a name.
老查尔斯·韦斯特莫兰德  才是那天被监禁的人
Charles Westmoreland Senior was the one locked up that day.
那么 你要不要钱?
Now, do you want the money or not?
无意冒犯 但这有点太容易了
No offence, but it's a little convenient.
你想加入 然后突然 你就变成那个人了
You want in, and suddenly you're the guy.
我怎么确信你现在没撒谎?
How do I know you're not lying now?
嘿 老头 别站在这里
Hey, Old Man River. Keep it moving.
嘿 苏克雷...
Hey, Sucre.
我对你和其他墨西哥人有个疑问
I got a question about you and the rest of the Mexicans.
我认为我帮不上你
I don't think I'll be able to help.
因为我是波多黎哥人
Seeing as I'm Puerto Rican.
从地理上讲就那个意思 朋友
Geographical semantics, amigo.
我是指那些有拉丁血统的人
I'm speaking about the general Latino population.
那么本想来懒惰的人
How is it that a people so historically lazy
为何会来到美国 成为体力劳动者的主力呢?
ended up being such a big part of the nation's workforce?
依我看来 是美国人懒惰
The way I see things, it's everyone else that's lazy.
不然 不会有那么多工作给移民的人
Otherwise, there wouldn't be jobs for the immigrants.
那些坐在家里关心失业的人 懒人...
The ones sitting at home,collecting unemployment, the lazy ones...
不是我们
it's not us.
你让他这么说你们的人?
You gonna let him talk about your people like that?
随便了 个人想法不一样
Whatever, Deliverance.
你知不知道? 我们现在是一条船上的人
You know what? We may be a team in here,
还有就是
but just so that you know:
当我们逃出去那一刻  我们就要各顾各的了
The minute we get over that wall, it's every man for himself.
或者比那还要早
Or sooner.
LJ?
你知道俄国人怎么杀人吗?
You know how the Russians do things?
他们先让你活着 然后杀掉你全家
They let you live, and they kill everyone else in your family
还有 所有你爱的人
and anyone you've ever loved.
听起来怎么样?
How's that sound?
-去死吧  -噢 来吧
-Go to hell.  -Oh, come on.
女士不该这么说话吧?
Is that any way for a lady to talk?
哦
What
怎么 你以为我是笨蛋吗?
you think I'm an idiot?
以为我会走到这井上面?
I'm just gonna walk into a well?
别犯傻了 多诺万女士
Seriously, Ms Donovan...
你还好吧?
You all right?
斯科菲尔德 别想偷懒
Scofield! No sitting down on the job
过来在我看得到你的地方干活
I want you out here working where I can see you.
马上就来 老大
I'm on it, boss.
快过来 斯科菲尔德  过来!
Move it, Scofield, move it!
嘿 布拉德  看到你真开心
Hey, Brad. Good to see you.
嘿 宝贝儿
Hey, baby.
请注意了  女士们先生们
All right, ladies and gentlemen
请把你们的双手举起 欢迎我们下一位美丽可爱的女士上台
put your hands together for our next lovely young lady Up on the main stage
欢迎贾斯米！
it's Jasmine
想不想单独跳个舞?
Would you like a private dance?
你何不坐下 咱们聊一聊
Why don't you sit down and chat for a while?
看看我们是否合适
See if we hit it off?
-您贵姓?  -布拉德
-So, what's your name?  -Brad.
-你呢?  -贾斯米
-Yours?  -Jasmine.
说吧... 我说的是你的真名
Come on, your real name.
-尼卡  -尼卡
-It's Nika.  -Nika.
这真是个好名字
That's a pretty name.
告诉我 尼卡  你丈夫对你在这工作有什么看法?
Tell me, Nika...How's your husband feel about you working here?
我没结婚
I'm not married.
我希望你是因为内疚而在说谎
I hope you're lying for the sake of titillation.
否则 你今天早上的探监就是违法行为了...
Otherwise, your little visit to Fox River this morning would have been breaking the law.
斯科菲尔德太太
Mrs Scofield.
我们...结婚了 但他们要我们都要撒谎
We are married, but they tell all the girls to lie.
为了生意好做点
It's better for making business.
我不是来找你麻烦的
I'm not here to get you in trouble.
我只是想多了解一下你丈夫
I just want to know a little more about your husband.
嗯 他是个非常好的人
Well, he's a very good man.
我也这么想 但就算是好人也会做坏事
I'm sure he is. But even good men do bad things.
你的口音  是从... 不要告诉我  布达佩斯  是不是?
Your accent. You're from, don't tell me...Budapest, right?
-布拉格  -布拉格...
-Prague.  -Prague.
你来了多久? 两三个月 我猜
How recently did you come over?Only a couple months, I bet.
你喜欢呆在美国?
You like it here in America?
呃  我必须得走了
You know I really I have to move.
他们不想我们在一个顾客呆太久
They don't like us to spend too much time in one spot.
我可不想去查你的移民情况...
Now, I don't want to have to check into your immigration status.
我只想知道
I just need to know
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德让你做什么 来交换你的绿卡
what Michael Scofield wanted from you in exchange for the green card.
什么也没有
Nothing.
他在国外学习时我们认识的...
We met while he was studying overseas.
移民局不会想知道你的那些准备好的故事
I don't want to know what you memorised for the INS.
现在 要么你回答我关于斯科菲尔德的问题
Now, you answer my questions about Scofield,
要不我就打电话 给我芝加哥警局的兄弟了
or I call my guy in the Chicago PD.
或许他会问问有关于你的问题
And maybe he starts asking some questions about you.
一张信用卡
Credit card.
他让我把信用卡给他 就这么多
He asked me to bring him a credit card. That's it.
是的  跟踪这电话  过来找我  马上
Yeah. Trace this call.Come and get me now.
新格莱尔斯 我在新格莱尔斯
New Glarus. I'm in New Glarus.
不用 谢谢 我自己带了
No, thanks. I brought my own.
多尔希·安德鲁·埃尔斯顿·佳比斯
Dorothy Andrews Elston Kabis.
11美国财政部出纳局长 1971
United States treasurer, 1971.
D.B.库珀 劫机那年
The year of the DB Cooper hijacking.
DI192589
Dl192589.
是那笔黑钱的第一张的序列号
The first number in the series of bills used in the ransom drop.
多谢你的历史课
Thanks for the history lesson.
你要是调查都会知道这些
All it proves is you did the research.
我也做过研究
Same as me.
你结婚了
So you're married?
呃... 不是传统概念的那种
Uh, well...Not in the traditional sense of the word.
斯科菲尔德 我们都是成年人了  把话说明白点
Michael, we're both adults. Put your cards on the table.
好吧 我先说
OK. I'll go first.
呃... 作为这里少数的几名女性之一
As one of the very few women around here,
我习惯用自己的方法对付那些
I'm used to a certain amount...
挑逗和性暗示
of innuendo and flirtation being thrown my way.
我并不喜欢
I'm not used to enjoying it.
听着  莎拉...
Look, Sara...
叫我"唐克雷蒂医生"  让我说完
It's Dr Tancredi. And please let me finish.
我不是个猜忌的女人 但我是个小心谨慎的女人
I'm not ajealous woman. But I'm a careful one.
但不知为什么  在你旁边 我做不到...谨慎
And for some reason,when I'm around you I'm not careful.
-你不需要  -不 我需要
-You don't have to be.  -Yes, I do.
你身上有太多谜了 迈克尔
There's so many questions surrounding you, Michael.
有太多了
There are way too many.
我们这样  呃..
So here's the deal. Um...
从现在开始 给你打针  只要是有关于医疗的
From now on, your shots, medical concerns,
没有问题  只要是病人-医生的关系
they're all fine, as long as it's doctor-patient.
但如果是那些私人问题 以及各人喜好
But personal questions and favours of any kind
我们以后不要再提起了
are no longer a part of our relationship.
你的那些有关于我的问题...
The questions you have about me...
你会知道答案的
There are answers.
奎因!
Quinn.
我都开始担心了 你们迷路了吗?
Hey, I was getting worried. You guys get lost?
我们想打电话给你来确认精确坐标
We called you again to pinpoint your signal,
可你没接
but you never picked up.
是啊 破手机没电了
Battery went dead on the damn cellphone.
没办法 是不是?
那么 你怎么样?
So, uh... How'd it go?
我一条腿断了
Well, I got a broken leg down here.
听着 我想也许我们把事情都搞砸了
Listen, you know, I think maybe we got off on the wrong foot.
你有上司 我有上司
You got bosses, I got bosses,
到最后 我们还是在一条船上
but at the end of the day we're all on the same team.
对吗? 我们都在收拾残局
Right? Just trying to tie up loose ends.
我再同意你不过了
I could not agree more.
你们能不能找个绳子或是梯子什么的?
Yeah. So can you guys get a rope,or a ladder, or something?
你要干什么?
What the hell's that?
嘿... 嘿!
Hey, hey! Hey!
在收拾残局
Just tying up some loose ends.
你这个婊子养的... 嘿! 嘿!
You son of a... Hey!
嘿 别这么做! 别这么做!
Don't do this. Don't do this!
求你了! 我的腿断了 我站不起来! 你们要帮我!
Come on, please. My leg is broken. I can't stand.
你不能就这么把他留在这儿 他会死的
You can'tjust leave him down there. He'll die.
他是唯一知道 我们没抓住布伦斯儿子的人
He's the only one who knows we don't have the Burrows kid.
唯一的人
The only one.
你是不是也想下去 丹尼
There's room for you down there too, Danny.
别把我扔在这儿!
Don't leave me like this.
别把我扔下! 求你了!
Don't leave me. Please!
求你了!
Please!
你今天回劳犯团吗?
Coming back to PI today?
在那儿让我有点不爽  知道吗?
It's getting kind of testy in there, you know.
我知道
Yeah.
我要弄清楚一些事
I just needed to find something out.
那是什么?
What the hell's that?
听
Listen.
我是不是应该听见点动静?
Am I supposed to be hearing something?
嘘 耐心听
Shh.Just hold on.
-听见没  -什么?
-There.  -What?
我们等了20分钟就为听这个?
We sat around here for 20 minutes waiting to hear that?
确切的说 是18分钟
18 minutes, actually.
就是这个
And yes.
-那是什么?  -关键
-What was it?  -Keys.
警卫的关键
The guards' keys.
晚上警卫在医务室窗户下面巡逻一次的
18 minutes between each time
时间间隔是18分钟
the guards pass the infirmary windows on their rounds at night.
囚犯在晚上出不去
Cons aren't allowed out after hours.
这是唯一找到时间间隔的方法
Only way I could find out the timing.
-那说明什么?  -说明...
-What does that mean?  -It means...
四天后  在逃亡日那晚
Four days from now, on the night of the escape,
我们有18分钟从医务室下的窗户逃出去
we'll have 18 minutes to get the bars off the window
包括我们七个人穿过电线和翻墙的时间
and for all seven of us to get across the wire and over the wall.
-那能办到吗?  -当然
-Is that doable?  -Of course.
什么事?
What's up?
没事
Nothing.
嘿 我见过这表情 怎么了?
Hey, I know that look. What's up?
挖到了! 挖到了!
I hit it. I hit it!
在那儿 管子! 我们挖到了!
The pipe!
兄弟们 兄弟们
Guys, guys.
说吧 迈克尔 告诉我
Come on, Michael. Talk to me.
你要先听好消息还是坏消息?
You want the good news or the bad news?
好消息
The good.
韦斯特莫兰德和他的钱到了
Westmoreland and his money are in.
-坏消息呢?  -我计算了一下
-What's the bad?  -I've done the math.
我们从医务室窗户翻出去要五分钟
It'll take at least five minutes for us to get the bars off the window in the infirmary,
每个人两分钟翻过电线和墙
two minutes each to get across the wire and over the wall.
所以?
So?
我们只有 18 分钟
We've only got 18 minutes.
我们已经太多人了
We've got too many people.
必须去掉一个
One of 'em has to go.